[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
It's starting! It's starting!
I trust that Your Majesty
is in good health.
You've already said your goodbyes,
so why do you want me
to take your clothing out?
Oh, my goodness.
Good heaven! Confound it!
All right.
You go ahead. Go to Hanyang first.
You… You mean alone? Why?
Hey, fool, what do you think?
That I came here for leisure?
Can't you see?
His Majesty sent me
to survey the construction site.
And now I've wasted a whole day.
I'm pretty busy as well, idiot.
Go on. Go ahead.
I just got to see Eun-sil.
My lady.
I've brought you a change of c…
clothing.
Wait.
Oh, my lady.
But when did you find the time to change?
Here.
This is…
How did you… Well…
Where did you even find these garments?
You are… remarkably quick.
There.
My lady.
Are you awake?
Excuse me, I'm coming in.
All right.
My lady?
My lady!
Since my husband's passing,
I have been burdened with shame and guilt
that I did not immediately
follow after him.
But now it seems the time has come.
I shall leave rejoicing,
because I know
I will see my husband again.
Hui-yeon.
May you remain in good health.
Hui-yeon!
It seems Hui-yeon has come
to see her brother for the last time.
She has gone far away.
Now listen.
Search the riverbed and every single well
and, if you must,
every single mountain within ten miles.
But come back with Hui-yeon's remains.
Yes, sir.
Eun-sil, go right now
to see the Left State Councilor
and tell him Hui-yeon
has passed away in dignity.
-Yes. Y-Yes, sir.
-Oh, my goodness.
My lord.
Yes? What is it you wish to say?
The truth is, since that day I've known
that taking one's own life
is an unpardonable sin.
Naturally, since God forbids
bringing harm to others,
it's just as bad to do it to yourself.
I felt I'd been given knowledge
I shouldn't have had.
That scared me.
And what made it worse is
that circumstance is how we met.
The same day you gain knowledge
you shouldn't have,
you run into someone
you shouldn't have met.
Despite it all…
I do love you very deeply.
My lord!
Have you had a pleasant journey?
It's been a while.
How have you been?
Fine, fine. Well, good tidings to you.
Young master! Oh, my! Young master!
-Has all been well with you?
-Yes, sir.
-Ah, I see.
-I'll be staying in the guest quarters.
-Well, yes, quite so.
-You can let this person use my room.
As you wish, sir,
but you want me to put a servant
in a bedroom of your house?
This person's not a servant.
And there are reasons,
so let's get to it, shall we?
This way, I'll show you.
"Since reading the letter
in the tobacco box,
I have been captivated
by your masculine charm, my lord."
That is what the young widow said.
Dear cousin,
she is about to lie back.
Her undergarments are within reach,
shall we say?
That scent is so enchanting.
Please wait here.
I shall go find the young lady.
All right.
"Filial piety and brotherly respect
lead to kind and compassionate action."
"Fine words," Confucius says.
"Fine words and insinuations"…
…"and insinuations are only rarely"…
…"are only rarely associated with virtue."
Concubine?
How can that be?
Look at this handwriting.
Wretched girl.
I should've been the one staying here.
Oh, look at the clock.
Crazy bitch broke it.
Huh?
Oh, my.
Mother!
Yes? Oh, you've come.
Did you find something?
I went to So-ok's room,
and I found this there.
Go on, read it to me then.
I'm drowsy. I can't keep my eyes open.
-Mmm.
-Uh…
"Young master,
I'm not sure you'll believe me.
It takes my breath away to think of you,
young master.
It makes me wet to imagine you,
and I quiver all night in my bed.
My legs…
keep spreading apart constantly,
and I have no thick hands to unravel me.
I miss you so much, young master."
You may leave now.
You may leave now. Quickly! Quickly!
Wait. What's this?
Did you really find this
among So-ok's things?
Yes, Mother.
Then I just can't think why…
Why?
"Young master."
"Young master"? "Young master"? My!
So-ok, you little minx.
I guess she must playact with his lord,
calling him a name of young master.
Pardon me? Oh-Oh, surely not.
What do you mean, "surely not"?
Then what do you think So-ok…
Oh, my.
It's, uh, not that.
-Oh. Oh, Mother!
-Please. That wench.
After I sent her
to serve as his concubine!
Oh.
Are you going out?
To see my brother-in-law
at Janganmun Gate.
Look after her well.
She may be tired from that long journey.
You know, you're the only one
in whom I can really trust.
Yes, sir.
Have a safe trip.
Everything in the letter I sent
the day before was a lie and a joke.
"Everything was a lie and a joke."
-"Everything was a lie."
-I was reminded of the feelings
I once harbored for Lord Cho Won,
so I teased him as a jape.
I pray you take my letter in good spirit
and pay it little mind.
I pray you do not trouble your heart.
And I humbly beg
your gracious forgiveness.
"Everything I wrote as a joke and a lie."
"Feelings I once harbored."
Let us through!
For goodness' sake,
there's too much to do right now.
Goodness.
The 60th birthday banquet
for Her Royal Highness requires men.
The palace will send people,
but there is much to do
to prepare the work.
You've made a good point,
but construction is advancing
faster than anticipated.
If we were to needlessly reassign people
while the work is coming along so well,
this would surely invite complaints.
That won't happen with me.
That's what I'm trying to prevent
with my plan.
I think this is precisely the way
to see this project through to the end.
Come this way, will you?
-Well, I guess it's all rather…
-I thought at last we could…
-Brother-in-law.
-Could what?
You're very busy now, I see,
so I shall take my leave.
I hope you will forgive me.
The matter's quite serious,
and we have much to deliberate.
Oh. Come to my quarters later.
A good chance to speak ill of your cousin
in her absence, don't you think?
All right then.
Of course. I can confirm that right away.
We have now furnished all the paper,
as arranged.
How shall I ever repay such a favor?
His Majesty's kindness
is no favor to be repaid.
All of Hwaseong is its beneficiary.
Yes, sir.
Ah, what are you doing? Hurry it up!
Do you think we have a week
to move one rock?
My lady, it is I.
May I enter?
Have you been crying?
Do you have regrets?
No, I chose to act as I did.
What could I possibly regret?
Then what is troubling you?
It was written that everything
was a lie and a joke.
I could tell something was amiss.
Still and all,
if you are only toying with me…
-If that's all this comes to--
-In my haste to escort you without delay,
I had completely forgotten
about that letter.
My apologies, my lady.
You're in such distress.
You should've come
to see me about it sooner.
You read the previous letter,
have you not?
There was another letter, you mean?
What?
It would seem you have passed
that letter along to the young widow.
I am moved to tears
by your deep consideration,
handing the young widow over to me
so that I may reap the reward,
dear cousin.
Well, it's come to this,
so I ought to begin with the first letter.
The story I'm going to recount
is rather intricate.
So I beg you, please make sure
your heart is prepared, my lady.
There was a time
when I roamed the provinces of Joseon,
writing of tobacco.
I met a tobacco merchant during that time
who was well-versed on the subject.
She said she could be of assistance.
When I was intoxicated
by the taste of tobacco,
my mind was in a haze,
her lustful appetite for me
was made very plain.
Indeed, one day she went so far…
…as to demand my attentions.
Not wishing to appear unmanly,
I feigned bravado.
And by the end, I acceded to…
to her lascivious and unspeakable
demands of me.
However…
just as the heat of summer falls quickly
from the red and brown autumn leaves,
my wandering period came to an end.
And I believe the time I spent
with that woman
has faded
before it could become a scandal.
And, alas,
having somehow found where I reside,
she recently sent me a letter.
And in that letter that she wrote to me…
she told me how she still lusted for me
in language so indecent.
I did not deign to answer.
Indeed, I intended to burn it,
but through my negligence,
it was mixed with my other letters
and found its way to you.
I was so ashamed and dismayed.
I had no idea of the proper way
to handle this matter.
So I went and sought her out
and beseeched her to write
that every word of that letter
was nothing but a lie and a bad joke.
I begged her on my knees.
How could you with her kind?
Because what I feel for you, my lady…
…is truer than ever it was,
and more sincere than anything
I've felt in my whole life.
It'll all be all right.
Now that you've told it all to me…
that horrible emptiness in your heart
shall be filled.
I can fill it.
This wretched past of mine…
These most shameful days I have lived,
and that have torn
your poor heart asunder…
How shall I ever express it
to you, my lady,
this self-punishment that I desire so?
It will all be all right.
I am so grateful, my lady.
My lady!
What am I to do with this? Oh, woe is me!
What am I to do
with this wretched past of mine?
Oh, wretched me!
How might you ever…
truly…
forgive me for my wretched past?
How could you ever respect ever again?
I gave the young widow some flowers,
and she smiled a little.
Mrs. Asan taught her how to make hwajeon,
and she made some.
And she told me that although the wind
may carry the fragrance away,
yet it shall linger in her heart.
And so I should gather some flowers again
around this time next year.
So hooray for spring, you say?
So you intend to stay until next spring,
when the brooks have thawed?
Oh, dear.
So you do not intend to die.
You want to go on living?
The young widow wishes
to continue living, I see.
Did you say she came back alone?
Oh, dear. What's happened?
-What?
-Oh, my.
-What has happened?
-Madam.
My lady has passed away to the afterlife.
Oh.
Oh, my lord.
My lady.
Is there something troubling
in your heart today?
Now, why would you ask me that?
Well, there's a bit of anger
in the flowers that you're painting.
Oh, that wit.
I wonder which of your parents
bequeathed you that.
Madam! It's Gye-hwa!
I have something urgent to tell you.
I have news about the Left State
Councilor's daughter-in-law's servant.
I'm told she has returned, but alone.
That was to be expected.
Tomorrow at sunrise, I shall call upon
the Lady of the First Rank.
Yes. I'll get everything ready.
All right, let's go.
I get the impression you're very unwell.
Is that the impression you get?
Yes.
My daughter-in-law's household
has sent word to me today.
It would appear,
she has breathed her last
while staying in their house.
What?
Am I understanding you?
Your daughter-in-law has passed on?
He will no longer be lonely, my Geum-ho.
I can take solace in that.
Although,
whether she purposely threw herself
into a river
or into a well, I cannot know.
Her body has not yet been found.
Good heavens.
I can't begin to imagine the…
the pain that you must be in.
Having shared fellowship
with your daughter-in-law,
I, too, am in a state of grief and pain.
But I cannot fathom how much sorrow
her death has caused your family.
Thank you, I…
My lady,
if I may be so bold,
there is one thing you could do
if you wish to help me.
Yes. I'd be happy to.
Please tell me how.
Surely a virtuous lady such as yourself
could present a petition
to His Majesty, should…
should any ungracious gossip get around.
That is, I--
Couldn't Lord Yoo be of any assistance
to you in this matter?
Yes.
I shall see to the matter.
"Surely a virtuous lady such as yourself
could present a petition to His Majesty."
"My lady."
Whoever thought one day
you'd entreat me like that?
-So-ok.
-Yes, my lady?
I won't be gone for very long.
Please do nothing to invite gossip
while I'm away.
I understand, my lady.
Safe journey.
All right.
Let's go.
All right, come on, come on.
Hurry. We must finish before sundown.
Hmm?
There is something I must tell you.
Pray come. I need you here.
I shall wait for you
at the study annex all night.
"Pray come."
-Hey! You wretch.
-Oh, you startled me! Who… Who are you?
-Be quiet. Quiet. Quiet, quiet.
-Mom?
In here. Come on, get inside.
Goodness' sake.
This love letter.
You were going to give it
to the young master?
-Yes.
-You crazy little…
For heaven's sake!
My lady gave me her permission of course.
Mother, what would you know
about the life of a Bukchon lady?
What is the meaning of that?
Whose permission did you get?
Your lady's?
Y-Y-Your lady…
Then do you mean to say
the lady of this house
is apprised of what's happened?
Yes, Mother, that's what I'm saying.
She also said that
it was quite all right with her.
Oh, and she also said that Lord Cho Won
would be of great service to me
and that I should go beseech him
to lend his assistance.
Now can't you tell?
There's no way
I could have made that line up alone.
Lord Cho Won…
Don't you think I know
what is worrying you, Mother?
Of course I do.
There's nothing to worry about at all.
You know, my lady and all the domestics
who work in this house,
they do not regard me
as merely a child-bearer.
Mother, are you listening to me or not?
Hush, you wretch.
And you wrote this love letter
with Lord Cho Won?
Well, I told you I did, so…
Oh, could it be you know Lord Cho Won too?
So-ok. Tell me plainly…
other than being schooled
in writing by that lord,
did something else… Did anything happen
when you were together?
What do you imagine we'd do?
Tell me the truth.
Nothing happened, really?
I told you. Nothing.
Huh?
Hmm…
Then I suppose you never noticed the mark
in the shape of a tiger on his chest?
Oh, does he have one?
Damn! I was the only one
without my clothes.
He never removed his garments,
so I saw nothing.
You…
Actually, now that I think about it,
I was in my undergarments.
Oh, I forgot.
What did you forget?
Could there possibly be something else?
-Mm-hmm.
-Seriously, you little--
Hey! It's not about me.
It's just something I heard.
I overheard when they were
in the lady's room whispering.
They said the Left State Councilor's
daughter-in-law's maidservant
came back alone in secret.
Of course, I don't know
what their true intentions were,
but I heard
what the servant girls were saying.
The daughter-in-law
who was supposed to be dead
might instead have skipped out
and fled by the light of the moon.
Fled by the light of the moon?
Eun-sil!
Go on ahead.
I know how sad you are
the lady you served has passed,
but that's enough now.
This family indeed
is greatly honored by this.
But unless you can stop your crying,
you'll be the object of disdain.
So then, what can I do?
Now that my lady's gone,
I know I won't be treated better
than a dog.
I have no idea.
Hey, stop weeping
or you'll earn their reproach.
Go see what's happening beyond the gate.
What was it, Chil-seong? Pal-seong?
The servant of the lord
who stayed at the annex is waiting there.
I was going to chase him away,
but I felt sorry for you,
so I'm telling you.
-Did you say he's called Chil-seong?
-Mmm.
Oh, dear.
How are you?
Heavens, you're so pale and thin.
I heard the lady you served
has passed away.
This is beef. Dried beef.
Here.
You must eat well,
despite the grief you taste.
The living must go on… must go on living.
It wasn't easy obtaining this,
so I hope you enjoy it.
Young master!
Young master, you have a visitor.
Well now, how is it that you come
without a word of warning?
Could it be…
that you have decided to reward me today?
There is something we must discuss.
Dear cousin.
Pray speak.
All Bukchon is reeling
because they all think
that she's passed away.
That's how it should be.
And now that's put a noose
around both of our necks, I must say.
Well, I'll be.
Things are getting interesting.
Won, listen.
You must stop this now.
Just put it back the way it was.
Surely you don't mean…
You want to put an end to our bet?
But why?
What a preposterous proposition.
If we continue,
if we let this wager go on,
our family's reputation could fall
along with your honor.
With my honor?
Huh?
You said my honor?
Oh, cousin.
Are you truly concerned over my honor?
From the beginning of our correspondence,
all I've done
was according to your wishes.
Though I longed
to show the world my independence
after failing so miserably.
Well, I began to think that I could
never do anything against your wishes,
as long as I live.
The bet stands.
And let the chips fall where they may.
All right then, you wait here.
Yes, ma'am.
Miss Yun?
Is that really you, Miss Yun?
It has been much too long.
You're quite right, it has, Mrs. Asan.
My lady?
My lady, it is you.
I thought you would
never be with me again.
Is this really how you're living now?
How could you be so imprudent, my dear?
I am so very ashamed.
If you had come to me,
if you had just explained, I…
I thought you were really gone
without saying goodbye,
just disappeared without a word.
How are they bearing up,
my father-in-law and mother-in-law?
All of those in Bukchon
think that you have died.
They all believe it was suicide.
You can never go back there again.
There is no going back.
What on earth
did you want to achieve by this act?
Did my dear cousin bring you here,
my lady?
I decided to come.
It was my choice
to follow the lord and come here.
For just a little while,
I wished to remain by his side
as any ordinary woman might.
How I envy your resolve, my lady.
I wish I could be so…
I wish I could be more like you, I guess.
I…
Hui-yeon is who I'd most like to be.
As a girl,
I learned proper writing skills
from my father.
I can imitate his writing now perfectly.
My lady, what is that?
"The Cheongyu Cho clan's scion, Won,
and your esteemed daughter,
Lady An Hui-yeon,
seek to form an honorable match and bond.
I humbly make this request
and await your consent, as is customary."
I am only his cousin, you see.
I can't consent on my own to this.
Madam, I… I'm not…
You said that you wished
to remain with my cousin
as an ordinary woman,
no matter how short or long.
Then do so.
Then you…
may pass away with grace and honor.
You must follow the destiny
which has been placed before you.
That's the only way to make amends,
to honor a woman who will,
for as long as she still draws breath,
never be called by her own name.
It's important you're aware.
My lady, I'm doing this for you.
Of course I'm aware.
Though I may call myself honorable
no longer…
I shall seek atonement
through death in the end, I know.
Do one thing for me.
But of course, tell me what.
The letters my lord and I exchanged
are in my room somewhere.
I should've burned them long ago.
I could not bring myself to,
so I left them there.
I only wished…
I could long for him just a bit longer.
Do not be concerned.
I'll take care. I shall see to all this.
My lady, as you go,
all you need to do
is put remorse behind you forever
and live out your days
to your heart's content…
in the company of my dear cousin.
Pray, do just that.
Young master.
You are late.
My cousin, has she departed yet?
Yes. She left already,
right after she saw the guest
in the room across the way.
My Lady Cho wrote it for you and me.
I wish to remain by your side.
Come, come.
We've scorned duty and decency.
Yet, I don't care what others think.
Pray, say those words back to me.
I, too, wish to remain by your side,
my lady.
I don't care what people think.